{
    "id": "00a641365790473d8a7dcd62a55b3ffa",
    "title": "One Word Substitution",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "aee8946e148d4f779e5bd8938a742b5c",
            "title": "One Word Substitution",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Which of the following words can be used to refer to a speaker who does not use more words than necessary?",
                    "description": "The adjective laconic is used to refer to people who say very little, but mean much.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Laconic",
                        "Taciturn",
                        "Inarticulate",
                        "Garrulous"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "Which of the following words can be used to refer to a man who excessively caters to, worships and submits to the most outlandish or outrageous demands of his wife?",
                    "description": "There is a difference between the words henpecked and uxorious. A henpecked husband is dominated by his wife. An uxorious husband is dominated by his neurosis, and his wife may not enjoy his uxoriousness.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Henpecked",
                        "Uxorious",
                        "Dipsomaniac"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "Which of the following words is synonymous with alcoholism?",
                    "description": "Dipsomania is the morbid compulsion to keep on drinking alcoholic beverages.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Dipsomania",
                        "Kleptomania",
                        "Pyromania"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "Which of the following words can be used to refer to people who have delusions about their invincibility?",
                    "description": "Megalomaniacs are people who have delusions about their invincibility.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Megalomaniac",
                        "Pyromaniac",
                        "Hypochondriac"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "Which of the following words can be used to refer to a person who fears shut-in or crowded places?",
                    "description": "A claustrophobe is a person who fears being shut-in or being in crowded places.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Arsonist",
                        "Agoraphobe",
                        "Claustrophobe"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "A person who sneers at convention and tradition is a/an ……………………………",
                    "description": "An iconoclast is a person who sneers at convention and tradition.",
                    "answers": [
                        "iconoclast",
                        "agnostic",
                        "atheist"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "A person who has morbid anxiety about his or her health is a /an ………………………….",
                    "description": "A hypochondriac is a person who has morbid anxiety about his/her health.",
                    "answers": [
                        "martinet",
                        "hypochondriac",
                        "tyro",
                        "virtuoso"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "Which of the following words is used to refer to the act of killing one’s wife?",
                    "description": "Uxoricide is the act of killing one’s wife.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Sycophancy",
                        "Patrimony",
                        "Patricide",
                        "Uxoricide"
                    ],
                    "correct": 3
                },
                {
                    "question": "Which of the following words can be used to refer to a person who is a strict disciplinarian?",
                    "description": "A martinet is a disciplinarian",
                    "answers": [
                        "Virago",
                        "Chauvinist",
                        "Martinet"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "Which of the following words can be used to refer to a person who tends to fixate obsessively over one thing?",
                    "description": "A monomaniac is a person who tends to fixate obsessively over one thing.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Hypochondriac",
                        "Agnostic",
                        "Monomaniac"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "Which of the following words can be used to refer to an accomplished musician?",
                    "description": "A virtuoso is an accomplished musician and performer.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Dilettante",
                        "Termagant",
                        "Virtuoso"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "Which of the following words can be used to refer to an old man in a ruling position?",
                    "description": "A patriarch is an old man in a ruling position.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Matriarch",
                        "Termagant",
                        "Patriarch"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}